# Dale F. Knapp

1909 Cynthia Drive, Champaign, IL 61821 217-390-5657 brendalek87@gmail.com

**Overview:** A highly dependable individual with experience in Manufacturing Maintenance and Automated Machinery with a record of accomplishment spanning several years. I have the ability to quickly resolve any given challenge. Areas of strength include: self-starter, ability to work in a team setting or individually and aggressive at problem solving.

#### Education:

### 1986 – 1987 ITT Technical Institute, Indianapolis IN

Graduate of the Bachelor of Applied Science Degree program in Automated Manufacturing Technology. Course included Advanced Math, Physics, Instrumentation, Hydraulics and Pneumatics, Manufacturing Organization and Management, Operations Research and Management, Industrial and Managerial Economics and Robotics theory and laboratory. Basic Computer Programming courses were also included and completed.

### 1984 – 1986 ITT Technical Institute, Indianapolis IN

Graduate of the Associate of Applied Science Degree program in Electronic Engineering Technology. Course included Hands-on training and study of Solid State Analog devices, digital and microcomputer principles. Communication Electronics, Pulse Techniques and Industrial Electronics. Troubleshooting and repair of circuits and electronic systems was a major area of training. Technical communication skills, both written and oral were also an integral part of the curriculum.

### **Professional Experience:**

### 2017 - present

## Hearthside Food Solutions, Gibson City IL

Maintenance Technician

Perform preventative maintenance and repairs on production systems

Complete changeovers and emergency maintenance on same production equipment

Complete projects given by the coordinator for the facility

Respond to immediate production and quality problems

## 2016 – 2017 Rockwell Automation, Champaign IL

Maintenance Technician

Perform preventative maintenance and rebuilds on conveyor systems

Perform, record preventative maintenance on building systems

Maintain maintenance department as well as keeping an accurate inventory on spare parts

Perform maintenance on different types of lift trucks and batteries for same vehicles

# 2015 – 2016 Menasha Packaging Company, Champaign IL

Maintenance Technician

Mechanical and electrical repair, troubleshooting of all production machinery and equipment

Perform changeovers and adjust same production machinery

Work closely with Production Supervisor and production personnel to keep machines operating in a quality manner

### 2011 - 2014

#### Frasca International, Urbana IL

Electronic Technician

Assemble, integrate, calibrate, test, debug and repair/retest of flight simulators Install audio/video, ethernet and AC power lines in flight simulators and in computer electronic cabinets for same simulators

Test flight simulators thru computer software then repair as needed

Solder, build cable and wiring harnesses as needed. Also make repairs and changes to existing harnesses using soldering skills on same flight simulators

Complete a checklist for flight simulators before shipping to customers

Work with appropriate Engineering personnel as needed to correct documentation errors, design problems, etc.

### 2010 - 2011

## Flex N Gate Corp. Guardian West Division, Urbana IL

Industrial Electrician

Perform preventative maintenance and work order repairs

Electrical troubleshooting and repair of various types of production machinery

Repair and/or replace different sizes and types of electrical conduit

Install new conduit and wires for new machinery and lights for production area

Assist with other technicians when needed

Boom lift and man lift certified

### 2006 - 2010

### Frasca International, Urbana IL

Electronic Technician

Assemble, integrate, calibrate, test, debug and repair/retest of flight simulators Install audio/video, ethernet and AC power lines in flight simulators and in computer electronic cabinets for same simulators

Test flight simulators thru computer software then repair as needed

Solder, build cable and wiring harnesses as needed. Also make repairs and changes to existing harnesses using soldering skills on same flight simulators

Complete a checklist for flight simulators before shipping to customers

Work with appropriate Engineering personnel as needed to correct documentation errors, design problems, etc.

### 2005 - 2006

### Solo Cup Company, Urbana IL

Mechanic/Technician

Maintain and repair production lid lines (15 machines)

Perform changeovers on same machines on a 3-man team

Perform repairs and preventative maintenance on 3 types of box tapers as needed

Correct quality problems by adjusting the same production lid lines

### 2004 - 2005

### TeePak LLC, Danville IL

Shirring Mechanic/Technician

Maintain and troubleshoot automated high speed shirring machine and casing equipment Troubleshoot, set up and changeover machines by using Allen Bradley Versa Views Replace equipment parts when worn out and/or no longer working. i.e. brake modules, belts, pulleys, cam followers and proximity switches Work closely with Production Supervisor

# 2004 Absopure Water, Champaign IL

Maintenance Technician

Mechanical repair and troubleshooting of production equipment

Work closely with Production Supervisor and Production Personnel to keep machines operating in a quality manner

Assist with new equipment installation

Perform quality checks every hour or after changeover was completed

#### 1993 - 2003

## Advanced Filtration Systems, Inc., Champaign IL

Maintenance Technician

Work closely with Production Coordinator, Production Manager and Support Manager

Fork Lift, Man Lift & Boom Lift Certified

Perform preventative maintenance

Electrical troubleshooting and mechanical repairing of different types of machinery

Assist with occasional new equipment installation

Install new wire conduit and replaced old conduit as needed

Install and wire in new A/C and/or D/C motors

Changed different types of sensing devices, banner eyes, proximity switches and photoelectric eyes as needed

Weld experience in all types of welding

Operate and performed preventative maintenance on several types of machinery

Work with other technicians and production coordinators in keeping production operating

#### 1988 – 1993

## Advanced Filtration Systems, Inc., Champaign IL

Machine Operator/Floater

Operated and assisted in all types of production machinery

Assisted production coordinator and other production personnel

Perform preventative maintenance

#### References:

Promptly furnished upon request.